# Ahmad Jiha

🖈 ahmadjiha.dev 🛚 in ahmad-jiha 🔘 ahmadjiha 💌 ahmad.j.jiha@gmail.com 🏴 U.S. Citizen 👂 Berkeley, CA

## **PROFILE**

Born in Los Angeles and am now based in the San Francisco Bay Area. I discovered a passion for code while pursuing a career in medicine when I taught myself how to automate repetitive medical research tasks. With this first experience, I began my software engineering journey. Currently, I am developing *Conifer*  $\varnothing$ , an open-source test parallelization framework.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Co-Creator, Software Engineer &

Jun 2022 - present

*Conifer* is an open-source test parallelization framework that speeds up End-to-End testing with Cypress. Conifer aims to increase developer productivity by addressing the context-switching costs incurred while waiting for large test suites to execute.

- Designed a test parallelization framework that allows users to split up a Cypress E2E test suite and run it in parallel on cloud-based infrastructure, speeding up test suite execution time by up to 3.72x.
- Automated deployment of a multi-node parallelization infrastructure using AWS's Cloud Development Kit (CDK), thus enabling an end-user to deploy the necessary infrastructure with a single command in under 10 minutes.
- Engineered a two-stage algorithm for efficiently allocating test files amongst the nodes of the test-parallelization
  infrastructure, allowing the test suite to be sped up on the initial run while enabling further optimization of later test runs.
- Designed a file-watcher utility for detecting and persisting testing artifacts produced by Cypress, allowing test results and metadata to be uploaded in real-time to persistent cloud storage such as AWS's S3 and DynamoDB.
- Created a live dashboard for visualizing test results using React, Express, and tailwind CSS, allowing end-users to view the
  results of a test run in real-time.
- Built a robust and easy-to-use command-line interface with Node.js, Commander.js, and Inquirer.js, enabling an end-user to run Conifer with just five commands.
- Collaborated with a remote, internationally distributed team of software engineers in an Agile environment, coordinating sprints, daily standups, pair programming sessions, and code reviews.
- Authored a comprehensive technical case study ② covering analysis of the problem domain, Conifer's specific use case, exploration and justification of design decisions, and discussion of tradeoffs.

Software Engineer Sep 2021 – Sep 2022

Launch School (Capstone Program)

- Developed open-source web applications utilizing various languages/technologies, such as JavaScript, Ruby, Python, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, and more, gaining proficiency with various databases, backend & frontend web development frameworks, and templating libraries.
- Selected Projects:
  - Track-It: A Trello-like project management board, built with Node.js, Express, React/Redux, and MongoDB.
  - RequestCapture: A RequestBin-like tool for capturing and inspecting inbound webhooks, built with Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Handlebars.
  - CartOut: A database-backed e-commerce application, built with Node.js, React/Redux, and MongoDB.

Research Assistant Oct 2019 – Sep 2021

THRIVE Lab, Department of Psychiatry, UCSF

- Automated subject recruitment and enrollment procedures, simplifying administration and accelerating study recruitment.
- Built an ETL pipeline for cleaning, standardizing, and importing clinical research study data into a Clinical Trial Management System, eliminating data-entry errors and reducing data processing times by 93%.
- Coordinated the development of a mobile app with a remote team of software engineers, enabling the execution of a remote clinical trial.
- Standardized and cleaned large datasets in Python, enabling statistical analysis of research data.

# **SKILLS**

# Languages & Frameworks

JavaScript, Node.js, Express, React/Redux, Cypress, Python, Go, Ruby, SQL, HTML/CSS, R, RStudio

#### Cloud

AWS (CDK, CloudFormation, ECS, EC2, Fargate, ECR, DynamoDB, S3), Digital Ocean Droplets, Heroku

#### **Technologies**

Docker, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Nginx, Git, GitHub, SSE, WebSockets, REST API Design, Redis

## **EDUCATION & TEST SCORES**

Medical College Admission Test (MCAT) Score: 524 (100th Percentile) Sep 2021

University of California, Berkeley
B.S. Business Administration - Haas School of Business

Aug 2019